# NOELIA ALCALÁ GARCÍA

Phone: +44 7858 922235

Email: nalcalag@gmail.com

Website: https://nalcalag.github.io/
GitHub: https://github.com/nalcalag

167/4 Easter Road EH7 5QB Edinburgh

I am a cheerful and positive person who enjoys developing native Android Apps. I love technologies and learn as much as possible everyday, whether studying a Master's, doing a course in coursera.org or in Lynda.com. I would like to find a native Android developer job where I can learn and grow personally and professionally. I am responsible, good at problem solving and work hard to achieve all my goals. I would like to use my experience and my adaptability to learn as much as possible.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming**: HTML, CSS, XML, Java, C++, Android SDK, Javascript, TypeScript AngularJS, Ionic, Bootstrap, JSON, Realm, SQLite, SQL, Swift, Wordpress.

Version Control: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, GitLab

Testing: JUnit, Espresso.

**Develop Tools:** Android Studio, Dreamweaver, Visual Studio, BonitaSoft, Xcode, Netbeans.

**Design Tools:** Photoshop, Adobe Ilustrator.

**Project Management Tools:** JIRA, Microsoft Project Professional. **Text Editors:** Sublime, Notepad++, WebStorm, Visual Studio Code.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### APS Group, Scotland

January 2016 - May 2017

#### Digital Media Engineer

APS Group is a marketing solutions & customer communications company. They support important companies throughout the whole marketing process from strategy to delivery. My duties involved:

- **Web conversions**: Follow a process to transform PDF documents to HTML/CSS code for Scottish Government Publications
- Web Development: Build themes from designs for Wordpress (PHP, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript)
- Android APPs development: We built an Android app for Church of Scotland Events. (Android Studio, Java, XML, Android SDK, Realm DataBase, JSON, Publishing apps)
- **Testing:** Formal process to verify and validate that deliverables fulfills all the requirements before publishing.

# ONO (Vodafone Company), Spain

June 2012 to April 2015

# Online Technician

The website of a company like Ono covers lots of content. During this time, I had the opportunity to specialize in the client area, help and support, and online store. My duties involved:

- Maintenance and management of improvements of the Online store: Manage every month
  marketing release deciding which new features had to be available on the webpage, keeping release
  notes up-to-date and team informed.
- **Troubleshooting:** Solve customer incidences on the website. Bug reporting and bug tracking using a CRM (Clarify).
- **Usability and testing:** We considered usability principles to make improvements or new projects on the website (Accessibility, Clarity, Consistency) and then we tested everything was how we required.
- **Project management:** Planning and defining scope (new or current customers, SMEs or particulars), time estimating, write requirements' specification and monitoring and reporting progress (JIRA and internal tools).
- Development of complaints and claims flows for customers self assessment (Software Development)
- Analysis Reporting: Collecting data from an internal tool about the sales on the online store, analyse all of the data, deliver ad hoc reports and present them to my supervisor and manager.

## Varadero Software Factory, Spain Internships as Web Developer

- HTML + CSS layout
- Testing and quality control

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

## **Master in Mobile Application Development**

2016 - Present

Universitat Oberta de Cataluya (Barcelona, Spain) Online

I would like to join the world's fastest growing IT employment sector by studying this Master with a full and in-depth training. It covers a wide range of programming languages and platforms:

- Fundamentals of mobile technology
- App development specifications
- Development of Android Apps (Android Studio)
- Development of iOS Apps (Xcode)
- HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript

# **Master in Professional Development**

2013 - 2014

University of Alcalá (Madrid, Spain)

This course gave me the opportunity to professionally improve thanks to the wide variety of business content studied.

### **Telecommunications Engineering**

2008 - 2014

The Polytechnic University of Madrid (Madrid, Spain)

Final degree based on the development of a self-management online tool for troubleshooting of TV decoder.

#### **Elektrotechnik (Erasmus Scolarship)**

2011 - 2012

Ostfalia Hochschule für angewandte Wissenschaften (Wolfenbüttel, Germany)

#### **COMPLEMENTARY TRAINING**

Android: Introduction to programming The Polytechnic University of Valencia (edX)	February 2016
Front-End JavaScript Frameworks: AngularJS The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (Coursera)	December 2015
Programming for Everybody (Python) University of Michigan (Coursera)	December 2014
Javascript, Jquery, HTML, CSS3 Netmind	February 2014
Specialized training in E-Care online ESIC Business & Marketing School	December 2012

# Languages

Spanish: Native Language

English: Upper-Intermediate Listener, Upper-Intermediate Speaker, Advanced Reading and Writing

German: Elementary Listener, Elementary Speaker, Elementary Reading and Writing